

# Nikola - Nino Acev

Experienced software engineer with a focus on building engaging & accessible digital experiences

#### **DETAILS**

078/300 - 905 ninoacev@gmail.com

# SKILLS

Programming languages JavaScript (ES2015+), TypeScript, HTML, CSS, Sass

**Libraries & Frameworks** React, Next.js, Bootstrap, Vue

# Tools & Platforms

Git, GitHub, Netlify, Contentful, AEM(Adobe Experience Manager), Storybook, Docker, Figma, ESLint

## LANGUAGES

English

French

## **PROFILE**

My journey began with an internship at Inscale as a .NET Core developer where I gained experience with MVC pattern and its features for building web applications. After the internship I accepted a role as a Software Engineer and Server/Network Manager at Intelligence agency of N. Macedonia, expanding my skills into a different field of IT.

This experience helped me realise my passion for web development inspiring me to apply for a front-end developer internship program at "Valtech" where my career as a developer began.

I am looking forward to join a team where I can contribute meaningfully, further develop my skills and grow as a web developer.

## **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

# Valtech, Skopje

NOVEMBER 2021 - PRESENT

- Building, styling, and shipping high-quality websites, design systems and cross-platform digital experiences for a diverse array of clients.
- Participation in story planning with PO/PM and users, estimation and breakdowns
  of large features, participation in design meetings with different teams, PR reviews.

# Software Engineer, Intelligence Agency of N. Macedonia

DECEMBER 2019 - JULY 2021

## **NET Core Developer, INSCALE, Skopje**

AUGUST 2019 - NOVEMBER 2019

#### **RELEVANT EXPERIENCE:**

- Front-End Proficiency: Skilled in HTML, SCSS, and JavaScript, with a strong focus on React/Next.js and additional experience in Vue.js. Adept at implementing mobile-first applications to deliver seamless, responsive user interfaces. Familiar with the BFF (Backend-for-Frontend) architectural pattern.
- Content Management Systems: Hands-on experience with AEM (Adobe Experience Manager) and Contentful headless CMS.
- Server-Side Rendering (SSR): Experienced in implementing SSR using BFF to serve data efficiently to the client.
- **Problem-Solving:** Adept at troubleshooting and resolving complex IT challenges in diverse environments.

## **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Computer Science and Information Technology University American College, Skopje

OCTOBER 2016 - MAY 2019

Web Design, SEAVUS "Education and Development Center", Skopje

OCTOBER 2014 - MAY 2015

# COMMUNICATION AND INTERPERSONAL SKILLS:

- Communicative person who works well in a team.
- Good listener, kind, respectful and always positive.